Jonathan Sutton

14 Newlyn Walk Bristol, BS42SL 07427585938 jonathan.sutton88@gmail.com

Until recently I was the Editor of a dedicated PC gaming and hardware website. Over the years I'd worked closely with our development team and gained a broad perspective of the workings of the site, and trying it for myself confirmed this was the move for me. I began learning a bit more about HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, before deciding to dive in head-first and teaching myself the ins and outs of web development. I am a highly motivated, self-starting developer who is adaptable and able to learn new things quickly, together with a strong eye for detail.

EXPERIENCE

C3 Marketing, Swindon —Web Technician

March 2021 - Present

Provide support on more than 100 WordPress websites, ensuring they are up to date and implementing the necessary fixes to keep them secure. Also work with clients to implement new features and changes as necessary.

Designed and launched several websites, ranging in size from one pagers through to 150+ page sites. Gained a deeper understanding of design norms and workflow, from pitching and proofing to clients through to site launches.

Manage hosting panels and oversee domain moves and hosting transitions

Got to grips with PHP on the job, largely self-teaching myself as and when specific features were required (such as Advanced Custom Fields).

Self-Employed, Bristol —Web Developer

January 2021 - March 2021

Began self-learning web development in September 2021, studying full time to gain a robust understanding of HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and ReactJS. From next-to-zero knowledge I completed my first commercial project in March 2021.

Designed and built various projects to flesh out my development skills, including profile pages, storefronts, surveys and tech docs using HTML /

LANGUAGES / KNOWLEDGE

HTML5

CSS

JavaScript

ReactJS

WordPress

PHP

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Photoshop

AWARDS

FCC Responsive web Design Certification

FCC JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
Certification

FCC Front End Development Libraries Certification

BA Hons in English Literature & Journalism

CSS; a palindrome checker, Roman numeral converter and working cash register in JavaScript; through to a dynamic drum machine, quote generator, and fully functional online calculator in ReactJS.

I am able to pool my front-end development and editorial knowledge to bring out the best from the final product.

Game Debate, Bristol — *Editor*

August 2013 - June 2020

Oversaw the day-to-day running of a website with millions of unique visitors every month. Wrote upwards of 40 articles per week, ensuring the news was covered swiftly and effectively, while generating in-depth features which helped drive audience engagement. Became adept at SEO optimisation, helping steer GD to become one of the largest independent gaming sites in the world.

Specialised in taking technical concepts and gearing them towards the layperson. Handle social media accounts, driving Twitter from ~400 followers to more than 24K. Responsible for thinking of, and implementing, new site ideas designed to enhance user flow and audience retention.

Pocket Gamer/Steel Media, Bath — Junior Reporter

May 2012 - September 2012

Worked on one of the UK's leading hand-held gaming news websites, preparing high quality editorial quickly and efficiently. Helped in the preparation of multimedia pieces and in the generation of ideas to encourage increased traffic to the site.

Mirror Football / MGN, London — Work Experience /Junior Reporter

May 2011 - July 2011

Worked in the online department of the Mirror Football website during the busy off-season, getting the opportunity to understand how a high-profile newspaper runs from the inside. Had the responsibility of seeking out news pieces and preparing them to go live within strict time-frames, learning the importance of live news in an online environment. Prepared multimedia pieces for the website, introducing interactivity into the features.

EDUCATION

University of the West of England, Bristol —

September 2007 - June 2010

BA Hons in English Literature & Journalism / 2:2

Milton Abbey School, Dorset —

September 2001 - June 2006

A Levels

- Grade A Communication Studies.
- Grade B English Literature.
- Grade C − Economics

9 GCSEs Grades A-C

MY PROJECTS

Front End Web Development Portfolio — *HTML*, CSS, JS and React Projects

I have a growing portfolio of web development projects, starting with HTML5 and CSS, through to JS, React, and my first commercial project: building a website for a high-end events and home dining start-up. www.jon-sutton.co.uk

www.elementsevents.co.uk

Wordpress Development Portfolio

I have helped develop and launch a number of Wordpress websites since joining C3 Marketing, including a total rework of their own website

https://c3.marketing

https://www.bartlettsbutchers.co.uk

https://www.soha.co.uk

https://www.themountinn.co.uk

https://www.keyway.co.uk